<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="h_nohelp">No info for this item</string>
    <string name="h_general">"
        Long tap any item to see a description of it.

        Exceptions:
        * Long tap on dropdown individual items is not supported, long tap the dropdown element instead.
        * Long tap on the speaker -/+ buttons allows to increase/decrease the frequency faster instead.
        * Long tap on the speaker scrollbar isn't supported. Simply changes the frequency.
        "</string>

    <string name="h_acc_head">"
        The accelerometer sensor contains three axis (X, Y and Z) which measure acceleration.
        Axis X is usually the horizontal axis (+x is at the right side of the screen, -x at the left).
        Axis Y is usually the vertical axis (+y is at the top of the screen, -y at the bottom).
        Axis Z is usually the cross axis (+z is on the front of the device, the screen, -z is at the back).
        Note that gravity is measured, so a typical device static on a table should show X=0, Y=0, Z=-9.81
        "</string>
    <string name="h_acc_txt">The currently values of the accelerometer, for each axis. Format \'{range} [min,max]\'</string>
    <string name="h_acc_mode">"
        Selects which values to display in the graph:
        - Raw: Raw data of the accelerometers directly measured by Android
        - Base: When selected, the current average raw values will be saved as the 'base values' and subtracted from the raw values. On a stationary device, after selecting this option the values should display 0,0,0.
        - Average: Displays the average value of the last 10 raw samples. Similar to a raw graph, but smoother.
        - Range: Displays the range value of the last 10 raw samples. Similar to a raw graph, but smoother.
        - FFT: Performs a Fast Fourier Transform of the last 200 samples.
        "</string>
    <string name="h_acc_clr">Clears the accelerometer graph. Usually not needed and performed automatically.</string>
    <string name="h_acc_rec">Starts recording the raw accelerometer values. While recording, press again to stop. Recorded values are saved on a new file in the format \"x_raw y_raw z_raw\" (number of lines proportional to recorded time).</string>
    <string name="h_acc_snap">Saves the currently displayed graph values (raw, range, fft…) on a new file in the format \"x_val y_val z_val\" (or \"hz x_val y_val z_val\" for FFT).</string>
    <string name="h_acc_graph">Graph with the values of the accelerometer. Check the selected mode (the dropdown menu above) for more information.</string>

    <string name="h_mic_head">"
        The microphone sensor uses the available microphone of the device or any external connected one to measure sound.
        It mainly records amplitude (max value of all the recorded samples) but can also display the internal buffer, check the dropdown above the graph for more information.
        "</string>
    <string name="h_mic_txt">The current amplitude of the microphone.</string>
    <string name="h_mic_mode">"
        Selects which values to display in the graph:
        - Raw: Raw data of the amplitude microphone directly measured by Android. This is the max value of all the samples in the buffer each instant.
        - Base: When selected, the current average raw values will be saved as the 'base values' and subtracted from the raw values. On a static environment, after selecting this option the amplitude should be zero.
        - Average: Displays the average value of the last 10 raw samples. Similar to a raw graph, but smoother.
        - Range: Displays the range value of the last 10 raw samples. Similar to a raw graph, but smoother.
        - Buffer: Displays the internal buffer used to measure the amplitude. In this mode the graph updates each frame (not a scrolling graph).
        - FFT: Performs a Fast Fourier Transform of the buffer values. In this mode the graph also updates each frame (not a scrolling graph).
        "</string>
    <string name="h_mic_clr">Clears the microphone graph. Usually not needed and performed automatically.</string>
    <string name="h_mic_rec">Starts recording the raw amplitude values. While recording, press again to stop. Recorded values are saved on a new file in the format \"amp\" (number of lines proportional to recorded time).</string>
    <string name="h_mic_snap">Saves the currently displayed graph values (raw, range, fft…) on a new file in the format \"amp\" (or \"x amp\" for Buffer; or \"hz amp\" for FFT).</string>
    <string name="h_mic_graph">Graph with the values of the microphone. Check the selected mode (the dropdown menu above) for more information.</string>

    <string name="h_spk_head">"
        The speaker actuator allows to play a tone with a specified frequency. Select a frequency with the seekbar and or the increase/decrease buttons (+/-) and press the toggle to play/mute. You can change the frequency while playing.
        Note: long tapping the +/- buttons will increase/decrease faster.
        "</string>
    <string name="h_spk_toggle">Shows the currently selected frequency. Press to toggle between play and mute.</string>

    <string name="h_vib_head">The vibrator actuator enables or disables the vibration of the device.</string>
    <string name="h_vib_tog">Toggles the vibration on/off</string>


    <string name="h_s_info">Opens a new screen with information of all the sensors in your device.</string>

    <string name="h_exp_frequency">"
        Runs the frequency experiment:
        For each frequency in the range [10,22010] Hz (step 100), plays it for a second and records the amplitude of the microphone, and the raw value of the three accelerometer axis. Then saves it to a file in the format \"hz amp x_val y_val z_val\".
        Remember to leave the device in a static surface and silent room. Expected duration: 3min 40sec.
        "</string>
    <string name="h_exp_volume">"
        Runs the volume experiment:
        For frequencies 100Hz, 1000Hz, 10000Hz and for each of the different volumes your device allows (usually from 0=mute to 15=full), plays it for a second and records the amplitude of the microphone, and the raw value of the three accelerometer axis. Then saves it to a file in the format \"hz vol amp x_val y_val z_val\".
        Remember to leave the device in a static surface and silent room. Expected duration: 48sec.
        "</string>
    <string name="h_exp_stop">Stops the currently executing experiment.</string>
</resources>